{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following types of Clostridium perfringens produces alpha toxin most abundantly?", "opta": "Type A", "optb": "Type B", "optc": "Type C", "optd": "Type D", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is predominantly proteolytic?", "opta": "C. sporogenes", "optb": "C. histolyticum", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "C. speticum", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following properties are the characteristics of tetanospasmin?", "opta": "It is a heat-labile protein", "optb": "It is a neurotoxin", "optc": "It can be toxoided", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Types of exotoxin, most commonly associated with botulism in man, is/are?", "opta": "Type A", "optb": "Type B", "optc": "Type E", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nagler's reaction is useful for the identification of", "opta": "C tetani", "optb": "C perfringens", "optc": "C botulinum", "optd": "C difficile", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most toxic exotoxin is", "opta": "tetanus toxin", "optb": "diphtheria toxin", "optc": "botulinum toxin", "optd": "cholera toxin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following species of Clostridium is predominantly sacchrolytic?", "opta": "C septicum", "optb": "C perfringens", "optc": "C novyi", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stormy clot reaction is useful in identification of", "opta": "C tetani", "optb": "C botulinum", "optc": "C perfringens", "optd": "C difficile", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Food poisoning strains of Clostridium perfringens belong to", "opta": "type A", "optb": "type B", "optc": "type C", "optd": "type D", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Reddening of meat in cooked meat broth is produced by", "opta": "C tetani", "optb": "C histolyticum", "optc": "Clostridium perfringens", "optd": "C sporogenes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Clostridium botulinum food poisoning is due to", "opta": "invasion of bacteria in the intestine", "optb": "preformed toxin", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Drumstick appearance is characteristic of", "opta": "C tetanomorphum", "optb": "C tetani", "optc": "C sphenoides", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Blackening of meat in cooked meat broth is through", "opta": "C histolyticum", "optb": "C perfringens", "optc": "C tetani", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Typical drumstick appearance of bacilli is generally seen in", "opta": "C perfringens", "optb": "C botulinum", "optc": "C tetani", "optd": "C histolyticum", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following(s) is/are obligate anaeorbes?", "opta": "C septicum", "optb": "C novyi", "optc": "C tetani", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}